<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cryptocurrency Cabal</title>
    <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cryptocurrency Cabal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/registration/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;course-registration:38a8983f478dea556d71617301415c7f&#34;&gt;Course Registration&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;due&#34;&gt;
Due: 8:29pm on Saturday, 29 August
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To register for the course, you need to &lt;strong&gt;setup a bitcoin wallet&lt;/strong&gt; (so
don&amp;rsquo;t wait until the last minute to do this).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://multibit.org/&#34;&gt;MultiBit HD&lt;/a&gt; is a good choice for this (but not for
storing large amounts!).  See
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bitcoin.org/en/choose-your-wallet&#34;&gt;https://bitcoin.org/en/choose-your-wallet&lt;/a&gt;
for information on bitcoin wallets.  Be aware that you probably do not
have time to download the full blockchain before this assignment is due,
so need to use a &lt;em&gt;lightweight wallet&lt;/em&gt; (we will learn what this means
later in the class).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After creating a wallet, you should find the &lt;em&gt;Recieving Address&lt;/em&gt; which
you will need for one of the questions.  If you used MultiBit HD, you
will see this by clicking &amp;ldquo;Request&amp;rdquo; (to request payment), and copy the
&amp;ldquo;Recipient Address&amp;rdquo;.  It should be a string like,
&lt;code&gt;19WmbY4nDcjAEv6wb5rcd5E6MutVMXBZzy&lt;/code&gt;.  Note that your wallet may create
several recipient addresses, so you won&amp;rsquo;t see the same address each time
you do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not necessary now, or at any time during this class, for you to
actually buy bitcoins with your own money.  If you are inclined to do
this, be careful, and don&amp;rsquo;t use any funds you cannot afford to lose!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Submit the form below (also avaible as &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1taP-16YrkyfNMjZxDkz5dF3BTaFd5wrDdIcZPq7OYmE/viewform?usp=send_form&#34;&gt;direct link&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1taP-16YrkyfNMjZxDkz5dF3BTaFd5wrDdIcZPq7OYmE/viewform?embedded=true&#34; width=&#34;760&#34; height=&#34;800&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginheight=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34;&gt;Loading...&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;syllabus:051025d606153e159a2b11ffecb897d5&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meetings:&lt;/strong&gt; Mondays and Wednesdays, 2:00-3:15pm in Olsson 120.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teachers:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans&#34;&gt;David Evans&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~sza4uq/&#34;&gt;Samee
  Zahur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Assistant:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pub/ori-shimony/b7/913/665&#34;&gt;Ori Shimony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office Hours:&lt;/strong&gt; Mondays 4-5:30pm (Ori, Rice 442); Wednesdays 3:15-4:30pm (Samee, Rice 442); Thursdays 2:30-3:30pm (Dave, Rice 507).  Office hours will be updated on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/calendar/embed?src=rmjagdrnmu3a9h2q5199lg4t28%40group.calendar.google.com&amp;amp;ctz=America/New_York&#34;&gt;course calendar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course Site:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://bitcoin-class.org&#34;&gt;http://bitcoin-class.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;hanging&#34;&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Readings:&lt;/strong&gt; We will not follow a textbook
closely, but will have several readings from two books (both of which
are freely available):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Andreas M. Antonopoulos,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aantonop/bitcoinbook&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mastering Bitcoin: Unlocking Digital
Cryptocurrencies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  (You can
use the free version of the book available at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aantonop/bitcoinbook&#34;&gt;https://github.com/aantonop/bitcoinbook&lt;/a&gt;,
but would probably benefit from buying the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Mastering-Bitcoin-Unlocking-Digital-Crypto-Currencies/dp/1449374042&#34;&gt;printed
version&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Arvind Narayanan, Joseph Bonneau, Edward Felten, Andrew Miller, Steven
Goldfeder. &lt;a href=&#34;https://piazza.com/princeton/spring2015/btctech/resources&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bitcoin and Cryptocurrency
Technologies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
This is a new book under development by a team at Princeton University.
(There are also lecture videos and slides that correspond to the book.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to those books, we will have several readings from both
general audience publications, technical documents, and research papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview:051025d606153e159a2b11ffecb897d5&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past 10,000 years, humans have been seeking better ways to store
and transfer value.  &lt;em&gt;Cryptocurrencies&lt;/em&gt; (most notably bitcoin), provide
a way to do this using bits alone without any centralized authority.  In
this course, we will learn about the cryptographic foundations for
cryptocurrencies; networking, software, hardware, and security issues
relevant to designing and implementing a cryptocurrency, and consider
the economic, legal, and political issues raised by cryptocurrencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;expected-background:051025d606153e159a2b11ffecb897d5&#34;&gt;Expected Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students entering this course are expected to be comfortable reading,
designing, and writing complex programs that involve thousands of lines
of code distributed over many modules.  You should be fairly comfortable
with math, at least enough to analyze probabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should be comfortable learning how to use a new programming language
features and APIs by reading their documentation (or source code when no
documentation is available), and not be surprised when you are expected
to learn a new language on your own or to seek documentation beyond what
was provided in class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students are &lt;strong&gt;not expected&lt;/strong&gt; to have significant previous experience with
cryptography (although such background will certainly be helpful).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some specific things we expect of students entering this course:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should have some experience programming in at least one
programming language, and not be afraid of needing to learn new
languages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You have written at least one program with over 1000 lines of code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should understand basic probability and be able to figure out
things like the probability that 100 tosses of a fair coin do not
result in any tails.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should understand at least as much about complexity and
computability as is covered in &lt;a href=&#34;http://dori-mic.org&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dori-Mic and the Universal
Machine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should find computing exciting and delighting, and believe you can
use computing to make the world a better place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not satisfy any of these expectations, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you
cannot take the class, but you need to let one of the course teachers
know about it at the beginning of the semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;honor-pledge:051025d606153e159a2b11ffecb897d5&#34;&gt;Honor Pledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course focuses on how to establish trust among distrusting people
using mathematics, computing, and networking.  As a student at
Mr. Jefferson&amp;rsquo;s University, you are intrinsically trusted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We take advantage of this trust to provide a better learning environment
for everyone.  In particular, students in this class are expected to
follow these rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;I will not lie, cheat or steal.&lt;/b&gt; If I am unsure whether something
would be considered lying, cheating or stealing, I will ask before doing
it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;I will carefully read and follow the collaboration policy on each
assignment.&lt;/b&gt; I will not abuse resources, including any submissions or
solutions for assignments from last semester&amp;rsquo;s version of this course,
that would be clearly detrimental to my own learning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the honor rules, students in this class are also expected
to follow these behaviors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;I will do what I can to help my fellow classmates learn.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;em&gt;Except
when specifically instructed not to&lt;/em&gt;, this means when other students ask
me for help, I will attempt to provide it. I will look at their answers
and discuss what I think is good or bad about their answers. I will help
others improve their work, but will not give them my answers directly. I
will try to teach them what they need to know to discover solutions
themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;I will ask for help.&lt;/b&gt; I will make a reasonable effort to do things
on my own first (or with my partners for group assignment), but will ask
my classmates or the course staff for help before getting overly
frustrated.  There are many ways to ask for help including the course
website and office hours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;I grant the course staff permission to reproduce and distribute
excerpts from my submissions for teaching purposes.&lt;/b&gt; If may opt-out
of this by adding a comment to your code, but without an explicit
opt-out comment we assume you agree to it.  Excerpts will be used
anonymously when illustrating a misunderstanding or common problem, and
with credit when showing an interesting or exemplary answer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;I will not invest money I cannot afford to lose in
cryptocurrencies.&lt;/b&gt; The main topic of this course is cryptocurrencies,
and students will be encouraged to gain experience using bitcoin to
conduct real transactions (but will not be expected to spend any
personal money on bitcoin).  Please be aware that bitcoin is very
volatile, and that you could lose all the money in your bitcoin wallet
if you make a programming error or lose your key. It would be foolish
and reckless to convert any money you would be upset about losing into a
cryptocurrency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;I will provide useful feedback.&lt;/b&gt; I realize that this is a new and
experimental course, and it is important that I let the course staff
know what they need to improve the course. I will not wait until the
end of the course to make the course staff aware of any problems. I
will provide feedback either anonymously or by contacting the course
staff directly. &lt;b&gt;I will fill out all requested surveys honestly and
thoroughly&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;assignments:051025d606153e159a2b11ffecb897d5&#34;&gt;Assignments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course will have one midterm, four problem sets, one final project,
and a (discretionary) final exam.  In addition, there will be several
check-ups (short tests in class, with opportunities to revise and
improve answers after discussion) and short assignments that may involve
reading assignments and posting answers and questions on the course
website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exams.&lt;/strong&gt; The midterm is Monday, 19 October.  The final exam is
scheduled for Friday, 11 December (2-5pm).  This time will be used to
schedule short oral exams for students who have not already demonstrated
strong understanding of the course topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem Sets.&lt;/strong&gt; The problem sets will involve writing programs and
solving problems to understand transactions in bitcoin (Problem Set 1),
bitcoin nodes and mining (Problem Set 2), blockchain analysis (Problem
Set 3), and alternate cryptocurrencies (Problem Set 4).  For most of
these assignments, you will be encouraged to work with one or two other
people in a small team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Project.&lt;/strong&gt; For the final project, you are free to work on
anything relevant to cryptocurrencies.  Some suggestions for project
ideas will be posted on the course website.  Students who have ambitious
ideas for a project may be able to arrange with the course staff to
expand the project to substitute for other assignments (such as Problem
Set 4).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;schedule:051025d606153e159a2b11ffecb897d5&#34;&gt;Schedule&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tenative and (continually) updated schedule is available as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/calendar/embed?src=rmjagdrnmu3a9h2q5199lg4t28%40group.calendar.google.com&amp;amp;ctz=America/New_York&#34;&gt;Google
calendar&lt;/a&gt;.
(You can view this calendar on the course site, or incorporate in as
iCal calendar into your own calendar using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/calendar/ical/rmjagdrnmu3a9h2q5199lg4t28%40group.calendar.google.com/public/basic.ics&#34;&gt;this
link&lt;/a&gt;.
Except when noted otherwise, assignments are due at &lt;b&gt;8:29pm&lt;/b&gt; on the
due date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main expected due dates:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday, 29 August: &lt;strong&gt;Registration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monday, 7 September: &lt;strong&gt;Checkup 1&lt;/strong&gt; (in class)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday, 15 September: &lt;strong&gt;Problem Set 1: Bitcoin Transactions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monday, 21 September: &lt;strong&gt;Checkup 2&lt;/strong&gt; (in class)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friday, 2 October: &lt;strong&gt;Problem Set 2: Nodes and Mining&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monday, 19 October: &lt;strong&gt;Midterm Exam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday, 27 October: &lt;strong&gt;Problem Set 3: Blockchain Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday, 17 November: &lt;strong&gt;Problem Set 4: Alternate Cryptocurrencies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sunday, 22 November: &lt;strong&gt;Project Proposal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monday, 7 December: Last class&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friday, 11 December: &lt;strong&gt;Final Exam&lt;/strong&gt; (discretionary)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dates shown here are subject to change based on how the semester
progresses, but with ample warning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading:051025d606153e159a2b11ffecb897d5&#34;&gt;Grading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We prefer to spend our time focused as much as possible on &lt;em&gt;teaching&lt;/em&gt;,
and as little as possible on &lt;em&gt;grading&lt;/em&gt;.  The assignments in this class
are designed to maximize &lt;em&gt;learning&lt;/em&gt;, rather than primarily for
&lt;em&gt;assessment&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, we understand that students do need to be assigned grades at
the end of the semester, and sometimes grades can be a powerful and
effective motivator as well as a useful way to measure progress and
understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grades will be determined based on your performance on all the class
assignments and class contributions (including postings on the course
site).  Some assignments may be graded by randomly looking at selected
answers, rather than reading everything submitted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no set weighting among these things, and in general, if there
is some combination of the above that demonstrates that you have gotten
what we hope out of the class then you will receive an A grade.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class 1: What is Money?</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/classes/class1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/classes/class1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;schedule:e795e40ef5a742faa33766b4d984e8c7&#34;&gt;Schedule&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;todo&#34;&gt;
Before &lt;strong&gt;8:29pm Saturday&lt;/strong&gt; (29 August):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://bitcoin-class.org/syllabus&#34;&gt;Course Syllabus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setup&lt;/strong&gt; a bitcoin wallet (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://bitcoin-class.org/registration&#34;&gt;Registration&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Submit &lt;a href=&#34;http://bitcoin-class.org/registration&#34;&gt;Registration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before &lt;strong&gt;Monday&amp;rsquo;s class&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aantonop/bitcoinbook/blob/develop/ch01.asciidoc&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chapter 1: Introduction&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aantonop/bitcoinbook/blob/develop/ch02.asciidoc&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chapter 2: How Bitcoin Works&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
from Andreas M. Antonopoulos, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aantonop/bitcoinbook&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mastering Bitcoin: Unlocking Digital
Cryptocurrencies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; book (also
available &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Mastering-Bitcoin-Unlocking-Digital-Crypto-Currencies/dp/1449374042&#34;&gt;in
print&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/md9EiU6QZoWroa&#34;
width=&#34;476&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34;
marginheight=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Note: ink markings may not appear in the
embedded viewer.  To see them, [download the slides](&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cryptocurrency Cabal</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/main/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/main/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;welcome-to-cryptocurrency-cabal:379caad01b6ea305187be199bcac1370&#34;&gt;Welcome to Cryptocurrency Cabal!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Class:&lt;/strong&gt; Wednesday, 26 August 2015&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; Olsson 120&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Teachers:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/evans&#34;&gt;David Evans&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~sza4uq/&#34;&gt;Samee Zahur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More information will be posted here soon.  Until then, see the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://bitcoin-class.org/syllabus/&#34;&gt;Syllabus&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;0/&#34;&gt;Last Semester&amp;rsquo;s
Course&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ombuds: Using Bitcoin to make online messages &#39;immutable&#39;</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/news/ombuds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/news/ombuds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an article about the Ombuds project created by Alex Kuck and
Nick Skelsey to use the bitcoin blockchain for communications:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.journalism.co.uk/news/ombuds-using-bitcoin-to-make-online-messages-immutable-/s2/a566167/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ombuds: Using Bitcoin to make online messages &amp;lsquo;immutable&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Journalism.co.uk, 20 August 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex and Nick graduated from UVa in Spring 2015, and helped develop the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://bitcoin-class.org/0/&#34;&gt;first offering of this course&lt;/a&gt;, including creating the PointCoin
cryptocurrency.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>