<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Announcements on Cryptocurrency Cabal</title>
    <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Announcements on Cryptocurrency Cabal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Final Project Reports</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/final/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/final/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The final project reports and sites are now posted: &lt;a href=&#34;http://bitcoin-class.org/project-reports/&#34;&gt;Project Reports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://bitcoin-class.org/images/lawn.jpg&#34; width=640 height=347&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
Thanks to everyone for your contributions to the class!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Enjoy winter break.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Ideas</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/project-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/project-ideas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;./projects/&#34;&gt;This page&lt;/a&gt; should contain everyone&amp;rsquo;s submitted project
idea.  We&amp;rsquo;ll keep this updated as the projects develop, so please let us
know if things change (you can also post comments on the page for
updates).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slides from Alex and Nick&amp;rsquo;s presentation are now posted:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;./classes/Crypto-Cabal-L21.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scaling Bitcoin and &lt;strike&gt;Web&lt;/strike&gt; &lt;strike&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/strike&gt; Blockchain 2.0&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Graph Isomorphism Hard?</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/graphisomorphism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/graphisomorphism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last class, we talked about using Graph Isomorphism as the basis for a
zero knowledge proof, based on the assumption that it is a
computationally hard problem to determine if two graphs are isomorphic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, Laszlo Babai presented a result that claims a quasipolynomial
time algorithm for graph isomorphism (that is, shows graph isomorphism
is not a hard enough problem to use as the basis for a zero knowledge
proof).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jeremykun.com/2015/11/12/a-quasipolynomial-time-algorithm-for-graph-isomorphism-the-details/&#34;&gt;Jeremy Kun&amp;rsquo;s summary of Babai&amp;rsquo;s presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rjlipton.wordpress.com/2015/11/04/a-big-result-on-graph-isomorphism/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Big Result on Graph Isomorphism&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that this has no bearing on the zero knowledge proofs based on the
hardness of graph three-coloring, which, unlike graph isomorphism, is
know to be NP-Complete.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Club Meeting</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/fbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/fbi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As Cyrus and Collin mentioned in class yesterday, Special Agent Jeremy
D&amp;rsquo;Errico, who visited our class earlier in the semester, will be the
guest speaker at the meeting of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cnsuva.io&#34;&gt;UVa Computer and Network Security
Club&lt;/a&gt; tonight (Thursday) at 7:00pm.  He&amp;rsquo;ll talk about
Cryptowall malware and efforts to analyze and detect it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meeting will be in Thorton D223.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Pre-Proposal</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project Pre-Proposals&lt;/strong&gt; are due &lt;strong&gt;Friday (November 13) at 8:29pm&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your pre-proposal should include the following information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Names of everyone on the project team - you may work on your own, or
with any number of teammates.  The expected impressiveness of your
project should scale at least as the square root of the number of
project members.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Title of your project - a short title that gets across what your
project is about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Idea for your project - one or two paragraphs that explain what
the purpose of your project is and what you plan to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Expected outcome - what you hope will be the outcome of your
project. This should explain what you expect to be able to deliver by
the end of semester, and how the world will benefit from it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Related work - list of projects (which could include papers,
companies, etc.) that had goals related to yours.  You do not have to
have studied these in detail yet, but should have identified starting
points to look at.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Immediate plans - what are the next steps you plan to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please submit this as a plain text email to
&lt;em&gt;ccc-staff@cs.virginia.edu&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your email should have as its subject line: &lt;b&gt;Project:
&lt;em&gt;Title&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt; where &lt;em&gt;Title&lt;/em&gt; is the title of your project.
It should include all team members as cc&amp;rsquo;d recipients.  It should
include your answers to the six points above, clearly numbered.  Do not
use any PDF attachments unless it is really necessary to provide a
figure for your idea to be understandable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PS3</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/ps3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/ps3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bitcoin-class.org/ps/ps3/&#34;&gt;Problem Set 3&lt;/a&gt; is now posted, and is
due Sunday, 8 November (8:29pm).  You should have received an email with
information on the bitcoin ransomware addresses to use for PS3.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monday&#39;s Class: Josh Cincinnati</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/josh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/josh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Monday&amp;rsquo;s class will be a guest talk from &lt;a href=&#34;http://bitbanter.com/&#34;&gt;Josh
Cincinnati&lt;/a&gt;.  Josh is
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blockcypher.com/&#34;&gt;BlockCypher&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Developer Advocate and
Comedian&amp;rdquo;.  He is a University of Virginia alum (Political &amp;amp; Social
Thought and Mathematics) and has an MBA from Stanford.  You can read
several interesting posts of his on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/blockcypher-blog&#34;&gt;BlockCypher
Blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some background on the current entrepreneurial landscape in cryptocurrencies, Josh send along this report:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://storj.io/TheBlockchainReport.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Blockchain Report: Welcome to the Internet of Value&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,
Needham &amp;amp; Company, LLC, 21 October 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midterm</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/midterm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/midterm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The midterm exam is here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://bitcoin-class.org/midterm.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extra Office Hours</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/extraoffice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/extraoffice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There will be some additional office hours next week:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monday, 5-6:30pm (Ori, Rice 442)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday, 2-3:30pm (Dave, Rice 507) &lt;strong&gt;(Added)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tuesday, 3:30-4:30pm (Samee, Rice 442) &lt;strong&gt;(Added)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wednesday, 3:30-4:30pm (Samee, Rice 442)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thursday, 2:30-3:30 (Dave, Rice 507)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope these will be helpful in preparing for the midterm, as well as
for discussing project ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midterm Schedule Update</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The midterm was originally scheduled for Monday, October 19, but due to
the two guest lectures this week it will be rescheduled to be on
Wednesday, October 21.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In class on Monday, October 19, you will receive a handout that sets up
and includes a few of the questions on the midterm (which you&amp;rsquo;ll be
expected to work on before Wednesday, Oct 21, and will be able to bring
in written answers to that you will submit as part of the midterm).  The
rest of the midterm will be in class on Wednesday, October 21.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a problem with the schedule change and prefer to do the
midterm on Monday, October 19, this is an option.  You should contact
Dave or Samee to arrange this by Oct 14 at the latest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PS2 / Projects</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/ps2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/ps2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bitcoin-class.org/ps/ps2/&#34;&gt;Problem Set 2&lt;/a&gt; is now posted, and is due
Friday, 9 October (8:29pm).  Sorry it took so long to post this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing I hope everyone thinks about over &amp;ldquo;reading break&amp;rdquo;, is
ideas for a course project.  You can see projects from the course last
Spring here:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://bitcoin-class.org/0/cryptocurrency-projects.html&#34;&gt;http://bitcoin-class.org/0/cryptocurrency-projects.html&lt;/a&gt;.
Your project can be anything related to cryptocurrencies or the tools we
learn about in this class, and can be done individually or with a team
(the size of the project should scale approximately with the square root
of the team size).  If you have an idea for an ambitious project that
you want to start early, it may be possible to arrange for it to substitute for some other course assignments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checkup 2 Revisions</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/checkup2revisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/checkup2revisions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you didn&amp;rsquo;t get a &amp;ldquo;gold star&amp;rdquo; on &lt;a href=&#34;./checkup2.pdf&#34;&gt;Checkup 2&lt;/a&gt;, you can
improve your score by answering one or more of the questions below.  You
can submit your revisions in class Wednesday, or at the end of office
hours Wednesday.  To submit revisions, attach your answers to these
questions to your original submission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R1. Hashing&lt;/strong&gt; (Answer this question if you want to improve your score on questions 1-4)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several different places in bitcoin where cryptographic hashes are used:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Producing the public bitcoin address by hashing the public key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B. Producing a transaction digest for use as the input in signing a transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C. Producing the Merkle tree root for authenticating the transactions in
a block (using hashes all the way up the tree).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;D. Producing the hash of the previous block to use in the block header.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E. Producing the double hash of the block (with nonces) to find a block
that satisfies the difficult needed in mining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose &lt;em&gt;H&lt;/em&gt; is a hash function that provides strong pre-image
resistance, but does not provide collision resistance. That is, an
adversary knows way to efficiently find pairs of values, &lt;em&gt;m&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;
and &lt;em&gt;m&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; such that &lt;em&gt;m&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; is not equal to
&lt;em&gt;m&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and &lt;em&gt;H&lt;/em&gt;(&lt;em&gt;m&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;) = &lt;em&gt;H&lt;/em&gt;(&lt;em&gt;m&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explain clearly &lt;em&gt;one place&lt;/em&gt; where cryptographic hashing is used in
bitcoin that the adversary could gain an advantage by knowing how to
find collisions in &lt;em&gt;H&lt;/em&gt;.  (Be careful to not overstate the advantage,
though.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R2. Blockchain&lt;/strong&gt; (Answer this question if you want to improve your score on questions 5-7)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ishtosa suggests strengthening bitcoin by adding the hash of the
previous previous block to the block header.  So, the block header for
block 534 would now include the both the hash of the block 533, and
the hash of block 532.  Would this be a good idea?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Checkup 1 Comments</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/checkup1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/checkup1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Here are answers and discussions for the Checkup 1 questions.  It would
not be at all surprising if there are one or two questions on Checkup 2
(scheduled for Wednesday, Sept 23) that are closely related to questions
on Checkup 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-what-are-the-most-essential-properties-something-must-have-to-be-used-as-a-currency:e149e2b552c6d9eb1457244b9601e8b3&#34;&gt;1. What are the most essential properties something must have to be used as a currency?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;
The two most essential properties are
&lt;em&gt;transferability&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;scarcity&lt;/em&gt;.  Recall that we defined a currency as
a &amp;ldquo;medium of exchange&amp;rdquo;.  In order for something to be used in exchanges,
it must be possible to transfer it from one owner to another.  The
second essential property of scarcity is intrinsic to having value.  If
something can be created or duplicated freely, it cannot be used to
represent value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being &lt;em&gt;universally recognized as valuable&lt;/em&gt; would be a
good alternative answer to &lt;em&gt;scarcity&lt;/em&gt;, but is a bit circular: nothing is
&amp;ldquo;universally&amp;rdquo; recognized as valuable for the entire universe; it is
universally recognized as valuable by all partcipants in an economy
using that currency, but this is a somewhat circular definition (of
universal).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other properties that were often mentioned, but are not essential for
something to be a currency include &lt;em&gt;stable&lt;/em&gt; (it is good in most cases is
a currency holds it value over time, but note that prefect stability is
generally not considered a good thing, and inflation rates should not be
zero for a well-functioning economy); &lt;em&gt;anonymous&lt;/em&gt; (some people consider
this desirable, but others view it as a negative; it is certainly not
essential for an effective currency); &lt;em&gt;decentralized&lt;/em&gt; (this is what
distinguished bitcoin from other currencies, but essentially all other
currencies used in the history of humanity have been centralized); and
&lt;em&gt;divisible&lt;/em&gt; (important for many transactions).
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-what-are-the-drawbacks-of-using-a-centralized-bank-to-record-transactions:e149e2b552c6d9eb1457244b9601e8b3&#34;&gt;2. What are the drawbacks of using a centralized bank to record transactions?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;
The biggest problem is that it requires placing a large amount of trust
the bank.  The bank can decide what transactions happened, and can
decide who owns what (including, deciding that the bank owns everything).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another problem with relying on a single, centralized entity is that
even if that entity is not malicious, it could still be &amp;ldquo;incompetent&amp;rdquo; -
if the bank is off-line, it is impossible to execute a transaction
(i.e., this is what happens when you try and use a credit card and the
merchant can&amp;rsquo;t connect to the system to do the transaction), and if the
bank loses the transaction record everything is lost.
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-where-is-asymmetric-cryptography-used-in-a-bitcoin-wallet:e149e2b552c6d9eb1457244b9601e8b3&#34;&gt;3. Where is asymmetric cryptography used in a bitcoin wallet?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;
The most important place is to sign transactions.  It is necessary to
use the private key associated with public address A to sign a
transaction that transfers a coin owned by A to another address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wallet is also using asymmetric cryptography to verify a transaction
(checking that a transaction that trasfers coin to your wallet is signed
by the appropriate private key using the public key corresponding to the
bitcoin address of the sender).
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;4-find-span-class-math-x-span-such-that-span-class-math-2-sup-x-sup-mod-7-1-span:e149e2b552c6d9eb1457244b9601e8b3&#34;&gt;4. Find &lt;span class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; such that &lt;span class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;2&lt;sup&gt;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; mod 7 = 1&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;
The simplest answer is &lt;span class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; = 3&lt;/span&gt; since &lt;span class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;2&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; = 8 mod 7 = 1&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any value &lt;span class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; mod 6 = 3&lt;/span&gt; satisfies the equation.  For example, &lt;span class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; = 9&lt;/span&gt; also works since &lt;span class=&#34;math&#34;&gt;2&lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt; = 512 mod 7 = 1&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;5-the-problem-in-the-previous-question-is-an-instance-of-the-discrete-logarithm-problem-why-do-cryptographers-consider-discrete-logarithm-to-be-a-hard-problem:e149e2b552c6d9eb1457244b9601e8b3&#34;&gt;5. The problem in the previous question is an instance of the &lt;em&gt;discrete logarithm problem&lt;/em&gt;.  Why do cryptographers consider discrete logarithm to be a &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt; problem?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;
Computer scientists consider a problem to be
&lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt; if there is no known algorithm that solves the problem with
resources that scale as a polynomial in the size of the problem
instance.  Discrete log is (currently) considered a hard problem because
the best known solutions are asymptotically not much better than trying
all possibilities until you find an input that works (that is, doing a
brute force search).  For a large enough input, the time expect to solve
a discrete problem can be made prohibative (given assumptions based on
what is known today).
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;6-alice-owns-coin-em-x-em-and-has-public-private-key-pair-em-ku-sub-a-sub-em-em-kr-sub-a-sub-em-bob-has-public-private-key-pair-em-ku-sub-b-sub-em-em-kr-sub-b-sub-em-for-the-strong-asymmetric-cryptosystem-e-the-notation-em-e-sub-k-sub-m-em-denotes-the-encryption-of-input-em-m-em-with-key-em-k-em-what-message-should-alice-send-to-the-public-ledger-to-transfer-em-x-em-to-bob:e149e2b552c6d9eb1457244b9601e8b3&#34;&gt;6. Alice owns coin &lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt; and has public/private key pair (&lt;em&gt;KU&lt;sub&gt;A&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;KR&lt;sub&gt;A&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;); Bob has public/private key pair (&lt;em&gt;KU&lt;sub&gt;B&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;KR&lt;sub&gt;B&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) for the strong asymmetric cryptosystem &lt;em&gt;E&lt;/em&gt; (the notation &lt;em&gt;E&lt;sub&gt;K&lt;/sub&gt;(m)&lt;/em&gt; denotes the encryption of input &lt;em&gt;m&lt;/em&gt; with key &lt;em&gt;K&lt;/em&gt;).  What message should Alice send to the public ledger to transfer &lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt; to Bob?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;answer&#34;&gt;
The message needs to be something (1) only Alice could generate and (2)
everyone can verify as transferring the coin to Bob.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;msg&lt;/em&gt; = &amp;ldquo;I, KU&lt;sub&gt;A&lt;/sub&gt; (Alice), transfer coin &lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt; to KU&lt;sub&gt;B&lt;/sub&gt; (Bob)&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
Send to ledger the message signed by Alice: (&lt;em&gt;msg&lt;/em&gt;, E&lt;sub&gt;KR&lt;sub&gt;A&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;(&lt;em&gt;msg&lt;/em&gt;))
   &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining Pools</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/miningpools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/miningpools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the up-to-date graph of hashing power distributed by mining pools
(that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to find in class Monday):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blockchain.info/pools?timespan=4days&#34;&gt;https://blockchain.info/pools?timespan=4days&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the current results for the past for days, more than 50% of
the hashing power appears to be held by just three mining pools: F2Pool
(20%), BitFury (17%), and AntPool (17%).  Each of these has around 75
PH/s (one peta-hash means 10&lt;sup&gt;15&lt;/sup&gt; computations of the bitcoin
block hashing function, which actually involves two computations of
SHA-256).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about mining a lot more in the coming weeks to get a good
understanding of what this means technically, as well as the
implications for the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Set 1 Posted</title>
      <link>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/ps1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bitcoin-class.org/announcements/ps1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bitcoin-class.org/ps/ps1/&#34;&gt;Problem Set 1&lt;/a&gt; is now posted, and is due Tuesday, 15 September (8:29pm).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
